<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile on Jare&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://thejare.github.io/tags/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile on Jare&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 10:07:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thejare.github.io/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Colors!</title>
      <link>https://thejare.github.io/2011/12/colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 10:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thejare.github.io/2011/12/colors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our little one loves to grab anything shiny, but is especially attracted to LCD screens of any type. He loves the netbook, the MacBook, my desktop&amp;#8217;s dual monitors, and of course the big TV, but most of all he loves the iPhone. I often activate the camera in reverse mode and let him play with it, but there&amp;#8217;s always been a problem: while he manipulates the phone, he will push some control or other and stop the camera, go to the desktop and start pushing random icons. I was wishing for some sort of &amp;#8216;baby mode&amp;#8217; where something neat would be happening on the screen, but controls would be disabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to use the Sunday morning to dust off my Canvas, CSS and JavaScript skills to code, with Alba&amp;#8217;s design input and feedback, a little BabySaver that could keep his attention with bright colors, and be impossible to quit for him. &lt;a title=&#34;Colors BabySaver&#34; href=&#34;http://www.iguanademos.com/Jare/temp/html5/BabySavers/Colors/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to see its current form. Click on the &amp;#8220;Endless&amp;#8221; button to enable interactions, otherwise any clicks will take you to my homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusion? He is much more interested in the iPhone&amp;#8217;s back, the plastic cover, and trying to eat them, than in watching the flying colors. And he still manages to open the iOS Notification Center pull-down, and from there go to the Message Center or some other app, in effect leaving the BabySaver. In typical &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;we know better than you&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt; Apple style, the pull down can&amp;#8217;t be disabled, not even inside native apps or as a global configuration setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, getting the CSS and scaffolding to work properly across browsers (including mobile Safari) was much more time consuming than programming the actual effects. Particularly disturbing was when the iPhone didn&amp;#8217;t like the &amp;#8216;Style&amp;#8217; button in the upper left corner: it worked fine in the beginning, but after adding the other buttons and the button style, it became unclickable (almost! With lots of trying, I could manage to click it). I have no idea why, and I couldn&amp;#8217;t figure out how to revert this behaviour. This, along with the Notification Center issue, is the reason the buttons are at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t tried it on any Androids or Windows Phones, but I have high hopes. Now that all the boring pieces are in place I&amp;#8217;ll probably try to write more effects and sounds to see how he likes them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback is welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>