<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>html5 on Jare&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://thejare.github.io/tags/html5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in html5 on Jare&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 01:27:02 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thejare.github.io/tags/html5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare 40</title>
      <link>https://thejare.github.io/2017/12/ludum-dare-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 01:27:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thejare.github.io/2017/12/ludum-dare-40/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made a little Ludum Dare 40 entry by the name of Idle Icon. &lt;a href=&#34;../../html/ld40/&#34;&gt;Try it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firedemo 20th anniversary</title>
      <link>https://thejare.github.io/2013/05/firedemo-20th-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 02:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thejare.github.io/2013/05/firedemo-20th-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been nearly 20 years since we released that old fire effect and the demoscene turned out to love it. I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iguanademos.com/Jare/files/Fire/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ported it to HTML5&lt;/a&gt; to celebrate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started when we bought a math coprocessor for our 386/25 and I started playing with fractals and plasmas. A few programming mistakes later, this thing came out and looked neat, so we slapped JCAB’s VT player and released it. Eternal gratitude to Jester of Sanity for unknowingly lending me his fantastic &lt;a href=&#34;http://mod.haxor.fi/Jester/mod.elysium&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;‘Elysium’ mod&lt;/a&gt; – it didn’t take me long to learn that such acts were VERY badly frowned upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheJare/FiredemoHTML5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;source code on github&lt;/a&gt; if you are so inclined. The comments are slightly better this time! This version runs rather slowly on Chrome, and I don’t really know why, but IE, Firefox (Win and Android) and iOS Safari work great.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpainJS</title>
      <link>https://thejare.github.io/2012/07/spainjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thejare.github.io/2012/07/spainjs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I had the honor to give a presentation at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://spainjs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SpainJS&lt;/a&gt; Javascript conference in Madrid, on the topic of Videogames and Javascript. I wasted a lot of time preparing a dynamic HTML5 page for my deck of slides, which was my excuse to play with CSS 3d transitions and fancy formatting. You can see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://iguanademos.com/Jare/docs/html5/SpainJS2012/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;dynamic deck&lt;/a&gt; (which needs Chrome/Firefox or a similarly decent browser), the &lt;a href=&#34;http://iguanademos.com/Jare/docs/html5/SpainJS2012/#all&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;static deck&lt;/a&gt; (should work everywhere), a &lt;a href=&#34;http://iguanademos.com/Jare/docs/html5/SpainJS2012/spainjs.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; I converted using &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/wkhtmltopdf/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;wkhtmltopdf&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/u/thejare/p/overview-of-javascript-in-games&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Speakerdeck&lt;/a&gt;, or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j4JmYAVjm1c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colors!</title>
      <link>https://thejare.github.io/2011/12/colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 10:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thejare.github.io/2011/12/colors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our little one loves to grab anything shiny, but is especially attracted to LCD screens of any type. He loves the netbook, the MacBook, my desktop’s dual monitors, and of course the big TV, but most of all he loves the iPhone. I often activate the camera in reverse mode and let him play with it, but there’s always been a problem: while he manipulates the phone, he will push some control or other and stop the camera, go to the desktop and start pushing random icons. I was wishing for some sort of ‘baby mode’ where something neat would be happening on the screen, but controls would be disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to use the Sunday morning to dust off my Canvas, CSS and JavaScript skills to code, with Alba’s design input and feedback, a little BabySaver that could keep his attention with bright colors, and be impossible to quit for him. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Click here&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; to see its current form. Click on the “Endless” button to enable interactions, otherwise any clicks will take you to my homepage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
